<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items from Pointy Hat's YouTube</name>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="magic-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-youtube/master/youtube/pointy-hat/magic-items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!--Horn of Plenty-->
	<element name="Horn of Plenty" type="Magic Item" source="Pointy Hat" id="ID_POINTY_HAT_MAGIC_ITEM_HORN_OF_PLENTY">
		<description>
			<p>A beautifully carved golden horn with a small hole on one of its ends and a large one on the other.</p>
			<p class="indent">This horn has 3 charges. When you use an action to blow it, you can cast the spell healing word at level 1 using your highest ability modifier, provided the target of the spell is within 60 feet of you and can hear you. Any sleeping creature within 30 feet of you is immediately woken up when you blow the horn and cast the spell. If you blow the horn after consuming all three charges, the horn produces no sound. The horn regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="charges">1d4</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://youtu.be/7BTxqnFK-4Y</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!--The Banshee Blade-->

	<element name="Banshee Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Pointy Hat" id="ID_POINTY_HAT_MAGIC_ITEM_BANSHEE_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This sword hums an almost imperceptible tune when wielded that only its user can hear. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic sword. As a bonus action, you can make the banshee blade either sing or shriek.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When the banshee blade sings, you select up to four creatures you can see, which can include yourself. The selected creatures add a +1 to their attack rolls when they are within 10 feet of the banshee blade.</li>
				<li>When the banshee blade shrieks, you select up to four creatures you can see. The selected creatures subtract a -1 to their attack rolls when they are within 10 feet of the banshee blade.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">While the banshee blade is singing or shrieking, you have disadvantage on stealth checks. The banshee blade sings or shrieks for 4 turns. Once the banshee blade has sung or shrieked, it can’t do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://youtu.be/-6uDXfB4BjI</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Empowered Banshee Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Pointy Hat" id="ID_POINTY_HAT_MAGIC_ITEM_EMPOWERED_BANSHEE_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This sword sings an inspiring song when wielded that only its user can hear. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic sword. As a bonus action, you can make the empowered banshee blade either sing or shriek.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When the empowered banshee blade sings, you select up to four creatures you can see, which can include yourself. The selected creatures add a 1d4 to all their attack rolls when they are within 10 feet of the banshee blade. You reroll the d4 each time a selected creature attacks.</li>
				<li>When the empowered banshee blade shrieks, you select up to four creatures you can see. The selected creatures subtract a 1d4 to all their attack rolls when they are within 10 feet of the banshee blade. You reroll the d4 each time a selected creature attacks.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">While the banshee blade is singing or shrieking, you have disadvantage on stealth checks. The banshee blade sings or shrieks for 4 turns. Once the banshee blade has sung or shrieked, it can’t do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://youtu.be/-6uDXfB4BjI</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Exalted Banshee Blade" type="Magic Item" source="Pointy Hat" id="ID_POINTY_HAT_MAGIC_ITEM_EXALTED_BANSHEE_BLADE">
		<description>
			<p>This sword chants a stirring hymn when wielded that only its user can hear. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic sword. As a bonus action, you can make the exalted banshee blade either sing or shriek.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When the exalted banshee blade sings, you select up to four creatures you can see, which can include yourself. The selected creatures add a 1d4 to all their attack rolls and saving throws when they are within 10 feet of the banshee blade. You reroll the d4 each time a selected creature attacks or makes a saving throw.</li>
				<li>When the exalted banshee blade shrieks, you select up to four creatures you can see. The selected creatures subtract a 1d4 to all their attack rolls and saving throws when they are within 10 feet of the banshee blade. You reroll the d4 each time a selected creature attacks or makes a saving throw.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">While the banshee blade is singing or shrieking, you have disadvantage on stealth checks. The banshee blade sings or shrieks for 4 turns. Once the banshee blade has sung or shrieked, it can’t do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS</set>
			<set name="sourceUrl">https://youtu.be/-6uDXfB4BjI</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
